redherring.com 2001-06-03

# RedHerring.com | The Business of Innovation

**RED HERRING  
PRIVACY STATEMENT**

Red Herring Communications Inc., through its various properties, including but not limited to Redherring.com and Stockmaster.com (hereinafter "Red Herring"), is committed to protecting the privacy of its customers and the users of this site. This statement explains how we achieve that goal and gives you details of our privacy practices, including a) what information we collect about you when you use this site; b) how the information will be used or disclosed; and c) your rights with respect to our collection and use of your data.

 _What Information do we collect and why?_

We may ask you to provide us with personal information on a voluntary basis in certain areas of our site. In particular, you may be asked to provide the following information:

  1. **Membership Information:** If you want to become a member of Red Herring you will be asked to provide general information, including contact details (such as your name and address) and demographic information (such as your employment details, financial status etc.. We will use this information to maintain your membership account with Red Herring and to keep you informed about products and services of Red Herring and other companies that we think may be of interest to you. You may elect not to receive such information by opting out as described below.
  2.  **Transaction Information:** If you want to order any information from our site, buy any of our products or subscribe for any of the services offered on our site we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including financial information such as a credit card number and expiration date and general contact details. We will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e. to deliver information, products or other services that you order and to invoice you. If the order is to be fulfilled by a third party, we will provide your name and shipping information to the third party for the express purpose of fulfilling the order.
  3.  **Survey Information:** If you want to participate in any of our online surveys you may be asked to provide personal information. The nature of the information may vary depending upon the type of survey that is being conducted, but will likely include contact information and demographic information. We will use this information, in aggregate form, to determine which products and services would be of interest to our users. The information gleaned from these surveys will never be sold to third parties nor will any user's information be personally identified or analyzed.
  4.  **IP Addresses and "Cookie" Information:** As is the case with many sites, our site logs your IP address and uses standard technology called "cookies", which are small data files that are downloaded onto your computer when you visit our site. Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Red Herring server whenever you interact with our site. If you prefer not to allow us to collect "cookie" information you can disable the cookies by turning them off in your browser, however, some areas of our site may not function properly if you do. We will use your IP address for systems administration purposes. We do not link IP addresses to any personally identifiable information. This means that your session will be tracked, but you will not be identified. We use cookies to track the pages that you visit on our site and to ensure that you do not see the same information repeatedly.
  5.  **Subscriber Information:** If you would like to receive our newsletters via e-mail, you will be asked for general information, including your e-mail address, name and zip code to facilitate our delivery of the newsletter to your account. We will also use this information to send you announcements of new Redherring.com features, newsletters and other special offers. However, you may elect not to receive these announcements by declining to register in the required field. 

Red Herring will hold all of this information on its computers in the United States of America and in Europe, and information may be transferred electronically from time to time between those locations. _How else does Red Herring use Information that it collects from this site?_

As well as using information about you for the specific purposes set out above, we may also use information about you for the following purposes:

  1. To send you information about Red Herring and promotional material about our products and services and products and services offered by other companies that we think may be of interest to you, provided that you have not opted out as described below.
  2. To monitor consumer interest in our range of products and services and to assist us in tailoring the content of this site to our online visitors' needs by collecting information about your preferences through tracking patterns of page-viewing on our site.
  3. To create a profile relating to you in order to show you the content that we think you might be interested in and to display the content according to your preferences. 

Red Herring has business relationships with other sites that provide additional information to our users or which we provide editorial content to (our "business partners"). We also have business dealings with companies that advertise on our site. Information that we collect on this site may be shared with those business partners and advertisers, but we will only give those partners general, statistical information. We will not give them any information that personally identifies you. In the event that one of our advertisers or business partners desires to send our users a message, the message will be forwarded to us, and we will send it only to those users who have not opted out of receiving such information.

**DoubleClick's Services:** Currently, our advertisements are served by DoubleClick, Inc. Red Herring takes no responsibility for any information collected by DoubleClick during the course of its business via "cookie" technology or otherwise. As Red Herring strives to provide the greatest level of privacy for its users, we encourage you to review DoubleClick's privacy policy. This policy offers users the option of denying its "cookies" when visiting any sites served by DoubleClick. For more information on DoubleClick's data collection and use practices, please refer to DoubleClick's privacy policy located at: <http://www.doubleclick.net:8080/privacy_policy/>.

 _Forum and Message Boards_

This site makes forums and message boards available to its users. You are not required to provide any personal information in order to use these areas but you may choose to do so. Please remember that any information that you choose to disclose in these areas will be publicly available; thus, you should exercise caution when deciding whether to disclose personal information. Red Herring cannot accept any responsibility for ensuring the privacy of information that you choose to disclose in these areas.

 _Your Rights_

  1. **Opt-out:** Although most Red Herring customers indicate that they welcome details of offers and other promotional material about Red Herring products and services and products and services provided by our business partners and advertisers, we acknowledge the right of our customers to choose. You will be given the right to opt-out of receiving such information whenever you are asked to provide information on this site. If you do not opt-out at that time, but later decide that you do not wish to receive future communications of this nature you can contact us as set out below, indicating that you no longer want to receive i) information relating to products and services provided by other companies; or ii) any information relating to products and services (including Red Herring products and services).
  2.  **Access and Correction:** You have a right to know about the personal information that Red Herring holds about you. You also have a right to correct, amend or delete the information that Red Herring holds about you if it is incorrect. If you wish to exercise these rights please contact us by post or e-mail at the address shown in the "Contact" section below. 

_Security_

This site incorporates appropriate safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy and privacy of the personal information we have collected and we have put in place reasonable precautions to protect information from loss, misuse and alteration. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as required and only authorized individuals have access to the information you provide us. 

_External Links_

This website provides links to various websites that we do not control as well as to our sponsors. When you click on one of these links, you will be transferred out of our website and connected to the website of the organization or company that you selected. Even if an affiliation exists between our website and a third-party website, we exercise no control over linked sites. Each of these linked sites maintains its own independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures. If you visit a website that is linked to our site, you should consult that site's privacy policy before providing any personal information.

 _Terms and Modifications to Privacy Statement_

By using this website, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. If you do not agree with these terms, please do not disclose any personal information through this site.

Red Herring may modify this privacy statement at any time, at its discretion and modifications are effective upon being posted on this site. You are responsible for reviewing this privacy statement periodically to ensure that you are aware of any changes to it. 

_Children_

This site is not directed to children and Red Herring does not knowingly solicit information from any child under the age of 13. Should a child whom we know to be under 13 send personal information to us, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child to inform him or her that we must have parental consent before receiving his or her personal information.

 _Contact Details_

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the privacy practices of this site or if you want to exercise any of the rights that you are given under this privacy statement you can contact:

Rafe Needleman  
Red Herring Communications  
1550 Bryant Street  
Suite 450  
San Francisco, CA 94103  

|  |    
|  |  Red Herring Press Releases  
---|---  
| Red Herring Team  
| Redherring.com  
| Red Herring Magazine  
| Red Herring Events  
| RedHerring.com Partnerships  
| Permissions  
| Jobs at Red Herring  
| Contact Us
